# Hello World

My name is Paweł Wojtarowicz, and I am currently working as a System Administrator in a reputable company for over seven years. In 2021, I decided to change my career path to a Python developer. Since then, I have systematically learned and expanded my knowledge by coding various applications.

Linkedln: https://pl.linkedin.com/in/pawelwojtarowicz

Email/Phone: wojtarowicz.pawel@gmail.com / +48 603-445-177

Tech stack: Python, Java, SQL, SQLite, Pandas, NumPy, Plotly, Flask, Streamlit, GIT, HTML, CSS, Bash,

UNIX, Docker, AWS-S3, Heroku

#### Projects

## **NBP Currency Converter**

The app that retrieves current rates via the NBP API and saves them to a local database. Each currency conversion is saved to JSON file and automatically uploaded to S3 AWS.

https://github.com/Pawel-Wojtarowicz/nbp-api

#### Streamlit Twitter

The app allows you to retrieve Tweets from selected users on given dates; Users can export them to CSV files and plot a simple chart. In the application, I used Twitter API, Twitter Scraper, Streamlit, Plotly, and deployed it on Render

https://streamlit-twitter.onrender.com

#### Twitter movie notification

The app sends one tweet daily informing whether the movie "Kiler" will air. The app connects to Twitter via an API and uses web scraping.

https://github.com/Pawel-Wojtarowicz/Python/tree/master/twitter

#### **Bricks**

I've aimed to build a Flask app that allows users to choose an official lego set, retrieve its components and find alternative MOCs to make. The app connects to the Rebrickable API. I used HTML, CSS and Flask to write the app and deployed it on Heroku.

https://lego-flask.onrender.com

You can view more on Github and Railway: https://github.com/Pawel-Wojtarowicz https://digital-cv-production.up.railway.app

#### Work History

### IT Specialist (iSeries 2nd level support) - SYSADMIN

Kyndryl Global Service Delivery Center, Wrocław

2021/08 - Present

- Support for the server operating system, system management software, and operating system utilities, including upgrades.
- Analyze and diagnose bugs, performance issues, and troubleshoot problems.
- Recommend operating system updates and configuration modifications.
- Applying patches to the operating system.
- Assessment of planned changes in the server environment and informing about any requirements supporting such changes
- Incident resolution and on-demand data recovery

### IT Specialist (iSeries 2nd level support) - SYSADMIN

IBM Global Delivery Center, Wrocław 2017/08 - 2021/08

- Planning and monitoring of application deployment to update customer platforms.
- Ensuring user satisfaction by installing enhancements, configuration, preventive maintenance, troubleshooting, and solving complex problems.
- Monitoring and scheduling of tasks. Scheduling and backup via BRMS.
- Examination of failed backups.
- High quality assurance, safety compliance plan, operational procedures to maintain stability and resilience. (Keep the operating system secure)

# IT Specialist (iSeries 1st level support) Command Center

IBM Global Delivery Center, Wrocław 2015/04 - 2017/08

- Performing daily system monitoring, verifying the integrity and availability of all hardware, server resource systems and key processes.
- Monitor customer changes, service requests, tasks with standard incidents and tool changes to agreed deadlines and processes to maintain stability.
- Skills required to operate the application and ensure the employee's current knowledge.
- Responsible for sharing, advising and educating others.
- Understand and follow the compliance requirements set out in the company's policy

Education

Computer Science, Bachelor degree

University of Opole, Opole 2010/10 - 2014/09